HAOUALA FERIEL

CYBER SECURITY ENGINEER

EXPERIENCE

Professional EXPERIENCE

CyberSecurity project: Phishing

Higher School of Communication of Tunis (SUP'COM)

(January - June) 2023

of Tunis (SUP'COM)

- · Automating Phishing Attacks Analysis and Remediation with SOAR
- Using the Shuffle platform to simulate, test, and response to a phishing attack.

End-of-study project / Internship student

NEW ACCESS For Bankers

(February - June) 2022

- Development and deployment of the Object oriented and web based Enterprise Applications using Java, J2EE and MySQL
- Implemented Java EE components using Spring MVC and Spring security modules.

Network/ cybsersecurity Projects

Higher Institute of Computer Science ISI

2020 - 2021

- Advanced TCP/IP Networks: TCP/IP protocol, IP Addressing, Subnetting, IP Routing, Application Protocols, IP Version 6...
- Administration UNIX: Installing configuration and upgrading operating systems in the physical virtual environments.
- Protocol vulnerabilities and network attacks
- Security mechanisms and protocols: Firewalls, Virtual networks (VPN), Intrusion detection systems (IDS), Vulnerability scanning, cryptography

Internship student / Network project

National Center for Informatics (CNI)

June 2020

• Monitoring of cable systems providing telecommunications, internet connectivity, and services to residential customers throughout Tunisian territory.

Hackhathon EXPERIENCE

Metaverse Tunisian Summit hackathon

First Prize

25 - 26 - 27 November 2022

• In our solution, we tackled an emerging technology by using Augmented Reality and AI.

Cybersecurity & SMART FACTORY Hackathon

Third prize

29 - 30 October 2022

• Among many researchers and startup owners, we have proposed a decentralised-based solution for cybersecurity in Industry 4.0.

TICAD 8 Innovation «HACK AFRICA AUTOMOTIVE».

First Prize

2 September 2022

• Smart troubleshooting application launched by The Industrial Minister and Visteon Electronics (a multinational company that manufactures advanced PCB Boards).

ASSOCIATIVE EXPERIENCE

Sup'Com Junior Enterprise

President September 2022 - August 2023 Skills: Leadership, Time Managment, Team Work, Attention to detail

IEEE ISI SB

Chairwoman MAY 2020 - MAY 2021

Skills: Problem-solving, Organization, Strategic thinking

Securinets Association | NCSC Congress

Sponsorship Manager

2020

Skills: Effective communication and negotiation, expertise in networking and relationship-building

PROFILE:

Persistent, detail-oriented Security passionate who's driven by a desire to create and implement solutions that provide indepth network security and monitoring of events and incidents.

Well-suited to contribute to the success of an organization and develop

my abilities in a new professional experience.

SKILLS:

Networking:

OSI, TCP/IP, UDP, ARP, HTTP, HTTPS, FTP, SMTP, SNMP, DNS, DHCP, VPN, SDN, IP Addressing, IPv6, IPv4, 5G, LTE/LTE-Pro

Programming Languages:

Python, Java, Bash, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C++, C, PHP, SQL

Network Security:

Firewalls, Cryptography, SIEM, encryption, IDS

Security Platforms:

Wireshark, Shuffle, Packet Tracer

Other Tools:

Visual Studio, Microsoft Office Suite, GitHub, MATLAB, VBOX

Languages:

TOIEC for English, Arabic, French

CERTIFICATIONS:

Introduction to Cybersecurity Tools & Cyber Attacks IBM | 2020

CCNA 1 v7.0 Introduction to Networks CCNA | 2022

EDUCATION:

CyberSecurity Engineer 2021 - Now Higher School of Communication of Tunis

Higher School of Communication of Tunis SUP'Com

Bachelor in computer science: Network and service administration 2018 - 2021

Higher Institute of Computer Science ISI

Mathematics Bachelor 2014 - 2018

Pioneer School of Ariana

CONTACT

+216 97 729 351

feriel.haouala@supcom.tn

https://portfolioferielhaouala.vercel.app/

